Finding Aid for the Lisa See Papers LSC.0564
UCLA Library Special Collections
Lisa See papers
1973-2016
UCLA Library Special Collections
See, Lisa
LSC.0564
45.2 linear feet (97 boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 1 telescope box, 1 oversize map folder, and 1 shoebox)
6.0 linear feet (6 unprocessed record cartons)
Lisa See is a best-selling Chinese American writer and a native Angeleno. Her works include historical fiction novels, a memoir of her biracial family's immigration and their role in founding Los Angeles's Chinatown, and mystery thrillers. In addition to manuscripts, publicity, and research, the papers includes correspondence, materials related to several exhibits See curated, appointment books and journals, and awards.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS UNPROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9946631173606533
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Lisa See, 2001, 2011.
Biography
Lisa See (Lisa See Kendall) was born in 1955 in Paris, France. She is best known for her historical fiction novels about the friendships and romances of Chinese women and Asian American women. She is also known for her memoir of the history of her family in the United States, On Gold Mountain, inspired by many hours she spent as a young girl with her paternal grandparents in Los Angeles' Chinatown. See received her Bachelor of Arts from Loyola Marymount University in 1979 when she began her ongoing work as a freelance journalist. From 1983 to 1996 she was the West Coast correspondent for Publishers Weekly. From 1983 to 1990 she collaborated on books with her mother Carolyn See and John Espey, collectively using the pseudonym Monica Highland. These books were Lotus Land (1983), 110 Shanghai Road (1986), and Greetings from Southern California (1986).
In 1995, St. Martin's Press published the nonfiction account of See's family, On Gold Mountain: the one-hundred-year odyssey of my Chinese-American family, a New York Times Notable Book of 1995. In 1996, On Gold Mountain was republished by Vintage. In 2000, See's opera libretto based on On Gold Mountain was the Los Angeles Opera's Voices of California inaugural production and premiered at the Japan American Theatre followed by the Irvine Barclay Theatre. She also curated several exhibits inspired by On Gold Mountain. She served as guest curator for an exhibit on the Chinese American experience for the Autry National Center (then the Autry Museum of Western Heritage), which also traveled to the Smithsonian Institution in Washington, D.C. in 2001. See then helped develop and curate the Family Discovery Gallery at the Autry Museum, an interactive space for children and their families that focused on her biracial, bicultural family as seen through the eyes of her father as a seven-year-old boy living in 1930s Los Angeles. See revisited museum work in 2003 when she curated a retrospective on Tyrus Wong that was the inaugural exhibit for the Chinese American Museum.
In 1997 See began publishing the Red Princess Mysteries thriller series, which includes Flower Net (1997), The Interior (1999), and Dragon Bones (2003). Flower Net was a national bestseller, on the Los Angeles Times Best Books List for 1997, a New York Times Notable Book, and nominated for an Edgar award for best first novel. In 2003 she also wrote the Angels Walk LA Chinatown guidebook to celebrate the opening of the Metro Rail Gold Line Chinatown station.
Her first solo foray into historical fiction, Snow Flower and the Secret Fan (2005), became a New York Times bestseller and won numerous awards domestically and internationally. Her books to follow have all been bestselling historical fiction novels focusing on the friendships and romances of Chinese women and Asian American women. These include Peony in Love (2007), Shanghai Girls (2009), Dreams of Joy (2011), and China Dolls (2014).
In addition to her work as a writer, in 1993 See began serving on the Board of Trustees for the University of California Press and is now a trustee emerita. She also served on the Board of Trustees for the Pacific Asia Museum from 2001 to 2002. See currently serves as a Los Angeles City Commissioner on the El Pueblo de Los Angeles Monument Authority. More information on Lisa See can be found on her website at www.lisasee.com.
Scope and Content
The Lisa See papers range in date from 1973 to 2011, and consist of manuscripts, correspondence, publicity, research, and awards related to the literary career of Lisa See. They also include materials related to See's curatorial work, including museum exhibitions based on her book, On Gold Mountain, as well as appointment books, personal notebooks, and undergraduate coursework.
Organization and Arrangement
The papers are arranged in the following series:
Writings by Lisa See
Correspondence
Publicity files
Research files
Exhibition files
Personal files
Awards and memorabilia.
Related Material
Carolyn See Papers (Collection 1397). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Women authors, American -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; See, Lisa--Archives.
- Writings by Lisa See
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  SERIES CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
  Scope and Content
  This series includes manuscript drafts of books, stories, and articles published by See. It also includes a proposal for an unpublished children's book, and unpublished scripts.
  - Article- L.A. Weekly, 6-12 Feb 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    "Susan Skye: An Apostle of Prosperity" (p. 4).
  - Screenplay: A Woman Who Had ..., 26 Jun 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    On title page: "A Woman Who Had Her Way An Original Screenplay by Lisa See"; "Reg. W.G.A. June 26, 1978 No. 203002".
  - Screenplay: A Woman Who Had ... (Box 2, Folder 3)
    On title page: "A Woman Who Had Her Way An Original Screenplay by Lisa See".
  - Screenplay: A Woman Who Had ... (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Articles- TV Guide, 10 May 1980; 24 May 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    "Stalking Dramatic Wildlife Shots for Television" (p. 19); "Celluloid Jungle: It's Not Nice to Film Mother Nature" (p. 26).
  - Articles- TV Guide, 4 Oct 1980; 28 Mar 1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    "Mason Adams of 'Lou Grant'" (p. 26); "Creating Photogenic Food for TV Commercials" (p. 35).
  - Article- San Francisco Chronicle, 2 Jun 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    "A Change of Face" (p. EE-1).
  - Article- Messenger, 10-24 Mar 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    "Lotus Land" book excerpt (p. 6).
  - Articles- TV Guide, 11 Jul 1981; 14 Nov 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    "TV's Animal Trainers" (p. 11); "Celia Weston of 'Alice'" (p. 13).
  - Articles- TV Guide, 16 Apr 1983; 24 Dec 1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    "Rene Auberjonois of 'Benson'" (p. 17); "Karl Michaelsen of 'Gimme a Break'" (p. 12).
  - Articles- TV Guide, 19 May 1984; 7 Jul 1984; 1 Dec 1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    "Albert Hague of 'Fame'" (p. 45); "Michael Gross of 'Family Ties'" (p. 10); "Shari Belafonte-Harper of 'Hotel'" (p. 20).
  - Articles- Sporting Times, Mar 1979; Jun 1979; Jul 1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    "Tales from Wimbledon Folklore" (p. 18); "Southern Californians Combine the Mental with the Physical" (p. 18); "Restaurant Review" (p. 18).
  - Articles- Sporting Times, Nov 1978; Dec 1978; Nov 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    "Jackie Hansen Races Against Herself" (p. 14); "Free on Wheels, Disco Skating Rolls American Variation" (p. 11); "Hindsight is Wonderful But Running Makes Him Happy" (p. 18).
  - Article- Forum, Mar 1979 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    "Who is responsible for birth control?" (p. 20).
  - Book- Lotus Land, 19 Jun 1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    In "The Book Review" from Los Angeles Times (p. 10), Lotus Land is listed number 15 under Best Sellers Southern California.
  - Articles- Twin Circle, 25 Nov 1979; 11 May 1980 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    "The Garveys Use Their Blessings to Bring Health to the Sick" (p. 19); "Garveys Strike Balance Between Home & Career" (p.3).
  - Articles- Sporting Times, Oct 1978 - Dec 1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Bound compilation of Sporting Times. Lisa See has articles in all issues except October 1978.
  - Article- Women's Sports, Jan 1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    "L.A. Women's Marathon" (p. 18).
  - Article- Writers West, May 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    "Collaboration with Champagne" (p. 7).
  - Article- Dynamic Years, Jan/Feb 1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    "Saving Face" (p. 40).
  - Publicity- Lotus Land, Jun 1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    One paragraph review of Lotus Land in Palm Springs (p. 119). Includes quotes from Monica Highland relating to the writing of Lotus Land.
  - Article- Calgary Herald, 7 Feb 1981 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    "Buffy Sainte-Marie" (p. 3).
  - Opera - Nice Letters, 10 May 1995-14 Jul 2000 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Correspondence and reviews relating to the opera On Gold Mountain.
  - Opera- On Gold Mountain, Circa 2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Score of the opera On Gold Mountain.
  - Opera- On Gold Mountain, 1-2 Apr 2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Libretto of the opera On Gold Mountain with comments and edits.
  - Opera- On Gold Mountain, 2 Apr 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Opera- On Gold Mountain, 2000; Thermal paper. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Contact lists; Los Angeles Opera program; and synopsis, notes, and libretto to accompany CD recording of the opera On Gold Mountain.
  - Opera - Casting Phase, 18 Feb 2000-24 May 2000 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Actors' resumes; audition, rehearsal, and performance schedules; and correspondence for the opera On Gold Mountain.
  - Opera - Production, 3 Apr 2000-2 Jun 2000 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Ticket sales reports, rehearsal/production schedules, contact lists, correspondence, libretto, etc., for the opera On Gold Mountain.
  - Opera - Marketing, 1 Jan 2000-13 Jun 2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Promotional material, news release, program draft, correspondence, etc., for the opera On Gold Mountain. Also includes a program for the Committee of 100 11th Anniversary Conference.
  - Opera- On Gold Mountain, 25 Oct 1999 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    One CD. Special equipment or further processing maybe required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
    CD of the opera On Gold Mountain labeled "Complete but sketchy Act I".
  - Opera- On Gold Mountain, 15 Nov 1999 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    CD of the opera On Gold Mountain partially labeled "Rough: Act1, 3B to Act 2 3C".
  - Opera- On Gold Mountain, 9 Feb 2000 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    CD of the opera On Gold Mountain partially labeled "Revised 'Alone'".
  - Opera- On Gold Mountain, 16 Mar 2000 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    CD of the opera On Gold Mountain partially labeled "'Big Band'".
  - Opera- On Gold Mountain, 5 Apr 2000 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    CD of the opera On Gold Mountain partially labeled "'Alone' revised with expansion after intro".
  - Opera- On Gold Mountain, 7 Apr 2000 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    CD of the opera On Gold Mountain partially labeled "Instrumental btwn. matchmaker & 3 wives".
  - Opera- On Gold Mountain, 9 Apr 2000 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    CD of the opera On Gold Mountain partially labeled "Big band instrumental".
  - Opera- On Gold Mountain, 16 Apr 2000 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    CD of the opera On Gold Mountain partially labeled "Overture".
  - Opera- On Gold Mountain (Box 8, Folder 9)
    CD of the opera On Gold Mountain partially labeled "Lost in her bouquet".
  - Opera- On Gold Mountain (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Opera- On Gold Mountain (Box 8, Folder 11)
    2 CDs of the opera On Gold Mountain, labeled "Sc.1 to Sc.8C" and "Sc. 9 to end".
    Two CDs. Special equipment or further processing maybe required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
  - Freelance Pieces, 1990-1993; Thermal paper. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    This includes untitled manuscripts regarding authors, books, booksellers, publishing, etc. It also includes book reviews of "Growing Up Asian American" by Maria Hong (with an attached agreement form from Book World), "Katherine" by Anchee Min, and "Moon Cakes" by Andrea Louie.
  - Articles - 1996, 19 Feb 1996 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Untitled manuscripts regarding authors, books, booksellers, publishing, etc.; book review of "Pearl S. Buck: A Cultural Biography" by Peter Conn. Also includes correspondence with Elaine Jesmer of Elaine Jesmer Public Relations & Publicity.
  - PW - 1993 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Untitled manuscripts regarding authors, books, booksellers, publishing, etc.
  - PW - 1994, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - PW Columns/Orig. Copies (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - PW Col - 1/87-12/89, 3 Nov 1988 (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
  - PW Col - 1/92 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Untitled manuscripts regarding authors, books, booksellers, publishing, etc. Two manuscripts appear to have the titles "How to Be Your Own Publicist: Working with Publishers to Promote Your Store" and "Bestsellers from the Bay Area".
  - Post Card Book Notes & Ms., 1988 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Manuscript, notes, press release, etc., relating to the book "Greetings from Southern California".
  - Precious Cargo (Notes), 1989 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Manuscripts, magazine articles, notes, etc., relating to "Precious Cargo".
  - 101 Jobs/Making Babies, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Manuscripts, magazine articles, notes, etc., relating to "101 Jobs Where You Don't Have To Type" and "Making Babies".
  - Cable, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Treatments for Cable Health Network; articles on wildlife shows and martial arts. Also includes material related to the "Writing for Your Life" conference at LMU for which Lisa See was event coordinator; periodicals; and correspondence.
  - Untitled Manuscript (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Untitled manuscript related to living on the Greek island of Patmos.
  - Articles- TV Guide, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Correspondence sent from the "TV Guide" Readers' Service relating to interview of actor Rene Auberjonois.
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 12 Jul 1993; 9 Aug 1993 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    "Ten Speed Rolls Out Tricycle Press" (p. 28) and "Len Deighton" (p. 58); "Harriet Doerr" (p. 420).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 3 Jan 1994; 24 Jan 1994 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    "No Quiet Centenary for U. of California Press" (p. 31); "Quake Damages Many Calif. Stores; ABA Hotels OK" (p. 9, with John Mutter and Bridget Kinsella).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 7 Feb 1994; 7 Mar 1994 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    "Ira's Adams Has New Books, May Speak at ABA" (p. 16); "Cohen Returns to Collins; New 'Day in Life' Books Set" (p. 15).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 25 Apr 1994; 23 May 1994; 30 May 1994 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    "Poet Wins $50,000 Poetry Prize" (p. 16); "Rival Vietnam Books Planned by Former 'Day in Life' Partners" (p. 30) and "Peachpit Promotion Offers Computer Safety Title for 90¢" (p. 31); "Short Fiction from Western ZIP" (p. 22).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 13 Jun 1994; 20 Jun 1994 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    "PGW, Kirsch Get Top Franklin Awards from PMA" (p. 13); "Small Presses, Bookstores Meet to Lament Literary Funding" (p. 20).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 18 Jul 1994; 25 Jul 1994 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    "Sierra Club Takes a Leave from Wilderness" (p. 25); "Sales Up at Waite; Releases First CD-ROM Catalogue" (p. 12) and "Poets, Presses Take to the Road with Lollapalooza" (p. 15)
  - Article- Publishers Weekly, 1 Aug 1994 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    "China Memories" (p. 22).
  - Publishers Weekly, 8 Aug 1994 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    Issue of "Publishers Weekly" in which Lisa See is listed in the masthead, but with no author attribution within the publication.
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 12 Sep 1994; 17 Oct 1994 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    "Robert K. Tanenbaum: 'I Believe in the American Dream'" (p. 71); "Moon Online Promotes Travel Books, Bookstores" (p. 15), "SCBA Builds Community" (p. 26), and "Technically Busy at NCIBA" (p. 28).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 7 Nov 1994; 21 Nov 1994 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    "SCCBA Trade Show Brings Children's Booksellers Together" (p. 26); "Election Aftermath: What Does It Mean for the Book Business?" (p. 20, with John F. Baker and Jim Milliot).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 5 Dec 1994; 19 Dec 1994 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    "Sonoma Indies Form Association" (p. 26); "California Readers Gather by Radio" (p. 19).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 6 Feb 1995; 13 Feb 1995; 20 Feb 1995 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    "A Public-TV Publisher" (p. 27); "Ventura Bookstore Fights Censorship" (p. 23); "Voyager, Apple in Battle Over Bundled History CD-ROM" (p. 109).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 13 Mar 1995; 27 Mar 1995 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    "'Buzz', St. Martin's Launch New Imprint" (p. 14); "American Pacific (p. S2), "Hawaii: Beyond Pineapples and Picture Books" (p. S8), "Oregon: Nursing Publishing Niches (p. S18), and "Washington: Regionalism and a Literary Look" (p. S22).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 1 May 1995; 8 May 1995 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    "Kenaf: A Paper Alternative to Ponder" (p. 10); "Apple, Voyager Bury Hatchet" (p. 24).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 26 Jun 1995; 10 Jul 1995 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    "New Prima Line Will Focus on Games" (p. 26) and "Productivity Offers Online News" (p. 29); "Peachpit Press Launches Web Site" (p. 15).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 23 Oct 1995; 4 Sep 1995; 25 Sep 1995 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    "Seattle Launches Own Book Fair" (p. 19); "Some Counsel on Indie Publishing, from Black Heron" (p. 27); "Getty Launches Art Titles for Kids" and "Good Turnout for 3rd SCCBA Show" (p. 25).
  - Article- TV Guide, 14 Jun 1986 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    "Martha Smith of 'Scarecrow and Mrs. King'" (p. 10).
  - Article- Publishers Weekly, 9 Jan 1987 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    "A Good Year on the West Coast" (p. 40).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 6 Feb 1987; 27 Feb 1987 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    "The Great Los Angeles Library Fire --and Its Happy Ending" (p. 36); "Carrying the Torch for Children's Books in California" (p. 104) and "Broadening Niches: Multilingual Children's Books and Movie Technology Guides" (p. 144).
  - Article- Publishers Weekly, 27 Mar 1987 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    "Mercury House: Moving Away from Fiction" (p. 24).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 3 Apr 1987; 24 Apr 1987 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    "Big Books, Small Screen" (p. 26) and "Opportunities Abound on PBS and Cable" (p. 30); "Regional Reissues Are New Directions in San Francisco and Honolulu" (p. 34).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 29 May 1987 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    "The Great L.A. Poetry Battle" (p. 52).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 5 Jun 1987; 12 Jun 1987; 26 Jun 1987 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    "College Stores CAMEX Show Draws Record Turnout in Anaheim" (p. 44); "Tube Power" (p. 49); "City Lights: Still Doing Things Its Own Way" (p. 34).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 31 Jul 1987; 28 Aug 1987; 25 Sep 1987 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    "Harper, San Francisco: Experienced at Weathering Change" (p. 49); "The need to Self-Publish AIDS Books" (p. 56); "Amok: Books on the Dark Side, for a 'Dark Time'" (p. 84).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 16 Oct 1987; 30 Oct 1987 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    "Crime: A new East-West Dialogue" (p. 25); "'Public Publishing': A New Approach by a Scholarly Press" (p. 41) and "Marion Zimmer Bradley" (p. 49).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 27 Nov 1987; 18 Dec 1987 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    "A Gala Set of Books Celebrates Hollywood" (p. 42) and "NCBA Moves Trade Show to Oakland Site" (p. 58); "Publishers Marketing Association: A Study in Multiple Strategies" (p. 33) and "Dean R. Koontz" (p. 44).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 31 Oct 1986; 21 Nov 1986; 5 Dec 1986 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    "Advocacy Press Helps Teenagers to Plan Their Futures" (p. 38) and "Medallion Books Pyramid Sales Program Aims for Consumers" (p. 41); "Appealing to Urban Teens (p. 26); "Jeremy Tarcher ..." (p. 24) and "2. Keep 'Mission Earth' Moving" (p. 32).
  - Article- Small Press, Jan/Feb 1986 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    "Small Press Distribution Inc.: Literature Only, Please" (p. 40).
  - Article- L.A. Times Magazine, 18 Jan 1987 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    "Cowboy Visionary: On the Trail of the Tall Tale With Louis L'Amour" (p. 22G).
  - Article- L.A. Times Magazine, 31 Dec 1986 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Proof of article "Cowboy Visionary: On the Trail of the Tall Tale with Louis L'Amour", along with letter from "Los Angeles Times Magazine" news editor, Joyce Miller.
  - PW COLUMNS/orig. (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
    Untitled manuscripts, with edits, on various people and subjects.
  - Original Copies [1 of 2], 1984 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Untitled manuscripts, with edits, on various people and subjects; correspondence with Andrew Mill of "TV Guide"; articles on Jackie Hansen, martial arts, and Tom Sturak; outlines for "Making Babies" and "101 Jobs ..."; notes.
  - Original Copies [2 of 2], 1979 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Untitled manuscripts, with edits, on various people and subjects; articles on synchronized swimming, wildlife shows, Steve and Cyndy Garvey. Also includes correspondence with various editors; "Proposal" for writer's conference.
  - Screenplay- Secrets (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Edited screenplay entitled "Secrets"; two pages of handwritten notes.
  - Screenplay- Secrets, 16 Nov 1987 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Edited screenplay entitled "Secrets" by Lisa See and Carolyn See.
  - Screenplay- Secrets, 16 Nov 1987 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Screenplay entitled "Secrets" by Lisa See and Carolyn See.
  - Articles- L.A. Times, 16 Dec 1990; 2 Jun 1991; 1 Dec 1991 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    "The Book Business' Billion-Dollar Baby" (p. 1); "Signs, Co-Signs and Tangents" (p. 1); and "Archaeologist, Classicist, Teller of Tales" (p. 24), an interview of Deborah Nourse Lattimore.
  - Book Review- L.A. Times, 15 Jul 1990 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    Review of C.Y. Lee's book "The Second Son of Heaven" (p. 15).
  - PW COL - 1/90-12/91 (Box 20, Folder 1, Box 19, Folder 7)
    Untitled manuscripts on various people and subjects. Includes one correspondence item to "Maureen".
  - Article- Angeles, Jan 1991 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    "Roses of Winter: New Year's Day in Pasadena" (p. 66).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 28 Jul 1989; 29 Sep 1989 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    "Southern California Children's Booksellers Association" (p. 194), "Northern California Children's Booksellers Association" (p. 194), and "Talk-Show Prep" (p. 201); "What Next for Quinby's?" (p. 32).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 20 Oct 1989; 27 Oct 1989; 10 Nov 1989 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    "Creating Big Books for Limited Areas" (p. 21); "In Praise of Banned Books" (p. 49); "NCBA Meets in San Francisco" (p. 39).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 24 Nov 1989; 26 Jan 1990 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    "'L.A. Times' Announces Book Prizes" (p. 56); "Knightsbridge: 'Quality Publishing for the Long Run'" (p. 399).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 23 Mar 1990; 30 Mar 1990; 27 Apr 1990 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    "From Kenneth Branagh and Norton: A Very Young Portrait of an Artist" (p. 55); "Sampling a Sales Conference" (p. 39); "In the West, a Flurry of Awards" (p. 42).
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 22 Jun 1990; 29 Jun 1990; 27 Jul 1990 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    "In the West, Diversity and a Little Daring" (p. 37); "ABA 1990" (p. 47); "The Art of Children's Books: Every Picture Tells a Story" (p. 212).
  - Publishers Weekly, 19 Jan 1990 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Articles- Publishers Weekly, 14 Sep 1990; 28 Sep 1990 (Box 21, Folder 1)